nutty almond paste with a little chew resistance and fluffy whipped cream.and one (semla)
That's what I will show you how to bake today.
And what you need to bake the perfect
The bran is:
room -temperature butter, salt, wheat flour,
eggs, fresh yeast,
milk, sweet almond, cardamom,
Water and icing sugar.
And that I will
Start with, it is to crumble the yeast in a bowl.
And this should only be stirred together until the yeast has dissolved in the milk before I have in any other ingredients.
-—-—-
So now the yeast has dissolved in the milk
and i'll go down with powdered sugar
As I don't think I mentioned
But at least it should be sugar in this dough.
Two eggs.
As you can exclude if you want but
They give a little extra juiciness to the bun.
A must for the bran: Cardamom
This is ready -ground but
If you want even more cardamom flavor, then you take entire cardamom seeds and mortar.
Room -temperature butter.
I don't know if you've noticed it yet
But so far all my ingredients have been room -temperature.
The milk, the yeast, the eggs and now the butter.
It is partly for the sake of fermentation.
But when it comes to the butter, it is important
that it is room -temperature for if you melt the butter
does it become a fluid and the more fluid you have
the more wheat flour you need in the dough
and a dough that contains a lot of wheat flour
becomes much more compact since it has been baked and we want
An airy bun bun so we use room -temperature butter.
-—-—-
And then i have in half of the flour
And a little salt.
But the salt and the rest of the flour we save until later
Because we do not want the salt to make direct contact with the yeast because then it disturbs the fermentation process.
Then we don't want to have all wheat flour at once,
Without a little at a time so we get a messy but still manageable dough.
Then the buns become the airiest.
Such something.
Now I just hip
Because I did this so many times but accurate instructions and dimensions
For how much flour and other ingredients
As you need, you will find that as usual in the description.
There is a direct link to the recipe.
Like this now when the dough slowly
but surely have started to go together to a messy batter then I have in a little
Salt and even more flour.
And as you see
so i have in a little flour at a time so i see exactly when it goes together to
a manageable dough and never cross the limit
to this compact and
Thick the dough that just becomes a dry and dull bun.
The dough, it should be kneaded for at least 10 minutes
in machine or double if you do it by hand.
And that is because we really want to activate the gluten in the dough
Like that now you divide the part into the same number of parts
As you want buns.
Do you want to make big bran
So you do it.
Medium -sized or small.
It's all up to you.
Want to weigh your buns before
You bake them so you can do it.
One usually says that
30 g of dough per bun gives minis selection
Or 60 g of dough if you want to do ...
Such there are ordinary ... who usually be in cafes ...
The most common
the size of the bran.
That's about
60 g per bun.
It's about this size.
Now the dough is divided into the same number of pieces
Like I want buns.
They weigh exactly as much
Which is wonderful
And now it's time to shape them into buns.
Now you want a resilient bun that is
Nice and smooth rolled.
The trick behind it
is simply to curse your hand
around the bun and pushes slightly lightly
while rotating your hand.
One pushes it as well as towards the table, couples the hand
and rotates at the same time.
It doesn't have to go fast.
And then you do this until you feel that
There is no joint on the bun.
And this is just repeating for all of them, yes
30 buns you have in front of you to roll.
Twice as many
If you make mini seems.
Now the buns are shaped and ready to be fermented
and is it that you don't want to bake all the buns the same day
Then you can actually freeze them uncoated
And unequal just before fermentation.
Because in normal order I ferment my wheat doughs
only once.
And that is because if
We will now take this up with the fermentation again:
And then ferment again.
Then you have swamped it
You ferment once.
And the advantage of that
In addition to being very good fermentation on the dough,
It is that you can do this to freeze the buns
Before they ferment and baked
And then you can take out and thaw and ferment
Whenever you are craving.
So you don't have to
Stand and make a new dough every time.
So I cover them here with a back cloth now.
So that they can ferment in peace and quiet.
At least 2 hours.
Now is the time to make the almond paste and personally so love
I am almond pulp.
And almost takes a little bad up
If someone has stabbed the almond paste
When I get served a holiday.
Much almond paste it should be
so you can either buy pre -roasted and peeled
Or you rub them with a kitchen towel
When they are just pre -roasted
Then the shell falls off super light.
I prefer an almond paste with some chew resistance
So I don't mix the nuts completely.
But it is entirely up to you how you want to do.
It smells so good.
And so I have in the icing sugar.
And a splash of water.
I actually think I should have in some salt ...
And so the almond paste is allowed to stand and go here in
the spirits bag until my
Semmel buns are fermented, baked
And the whipped cream whipped.
Now it's a few hours later and my
Semmel buns have yeast to almost
More than twice as big.
Which is perfect this will really be wonderfully fluffy
And airy buns that I love.
Now I will brush them with a mixture of
eggs, water and salt.
And why I have in water and salt
in this mixture, it is for the egg not to clump
so that we really get a nice brush
on the buns.
So I just break down the egg here.
And so i have in
some water.
One just splashes, it's not so careful.
And a little, a little salty.
And whisk
This gently together.
Until it is not clumsy, but a smooth and yellow batter.
That's how.
Do you see completely lump -free so that